Inventory of the Arthur Kemp papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- World War II Subject File, 1923-1955 (Box 15-34)
  - United States
    - Price controls
      - General. Letter, statistics, memoranda, bulletins, and circulated documents, 1939-1943 (Folder 34: 2)
      - Herbert Hoover testimony, 1941 (Folder 34: 3)
        See also Herbert Hoover Speeches and Writings/Testimony before United States Senate Committee on Banking and Currency re price controls, 1941 December 16
      - Legislation. Draft bills, 1941-1942 (Folder 34: 4)
    - Rubber industry. Letters, study, and printed article, 1942 (Folder 34: 5)
    - Sugar industry. Report and clippings, 1942 (Folder 34: 6)
    - Taxation. Memorandum, speeches, circulated documents, and printed articles, 1944-1945 (Folder 34: 7)
    - United States. Office of War Information. Letters, press releases, reports, bulletins, pamphlets, and clippings, 1940s (Folder 34: 8)
      Includes Battle Stations for All; Facts about the United Nations; Proposals for a Free World; Tale of a City
- Declassified U.S. Government Records, 1941-1949 (Box 34)
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover
  - 2015 May release of records, 1941-1949 (Box-folder 34: 9-10)
    The first folder includes: a typescript of military strength of various European countries (undated); translations of meeting minutes from Hitler's headquarters (1941); a memorandum on the background of political developments leading to Pearl Harbor, based on a conversation with Prince Konoye (1945); a typescript of the military strength of Russian satellite countries in Europe (1947); and a report titled "Unification or Coordination: The Armed Forces Problem" (1949)
    The second folder includes: "Report of Subcommittee on Petroleum Economics to the Petroleum Industry War Council" (1942); memoranda on land reform from the Berlin Intelligence Staff (1946-1947); a chart titled "Possible Distribution of World Supplies 1947/48" (1947); and a chart titled "Per Capita Food Consumption in ERP Countries: Potential 1949-50 Levels, with Comparisons" (1949)
- General Subject File, 1918-1959 (Box 35-38)
  Correspondence, memoranda, notes, printed matter, and typed transcripts from printed sources, arranged by topic
  - Acheson, Dean. Memoranda, notes, clippings, printed articles, Congressional speeches, and typed excerpts from printed sources, 1945-1952 (Folder 35: 1)
  - American Relief Administration. Correspondence, reports, memoranda, notes, statements, statistics, printed articles, and typed excerpts from printed sources, 1918-1948, relating to American Relief Administration operations in Russia, 1919-1925 (Folder 35: 2)
    Includes United States Department of State printed report Memorandum on Certain Aspects of the Bolshevist Movement in Russia. See also Herbert Hoover Speeches and Writings/Statements re American Relief Administration operations in Russia
  - ANZUS Pact. Clippings, 1952 (Folder 35: 3)
  - Asia. Memorandum, clippings, and printed articles, 1952-1953 (Folder 35: 4)
  - Aviation. Statements by Juan T. Trippe and others, and Port of New York Authority study "Transportation by Helicopter,", 1947-1952 (Folder 35: 5)
  - Belarus. Nezalezhnaia Belarus' newspaper issue, 1953 (Folder 35: 6)
  - China
    - Correspondence, 1951-1952 (Folder 35: 7)
      Includes letter by Albert C. Wedemeyer, with mimeographed copy of Wedemeyer's 1947 report to the President
    - Memoranda, bulletin, and typed excerpts from printed sources, 1945-1953 (Folder 35: 8)
    - Printed matter. Clippings, printed articles, Congressional speeches, and printed excerpts, 1947-1955 (Folder 35: 9)
  - City management. New York City Management Survey Committee report and slum clearance report, 1952-1953 (Folder 35: 10)
  - Economics. Memoranda, letters, statistics, International Monetary Fund report, clippings, and printed articles, 1949-1955 (Folder 36: 1)
    Includes correspondence with Mark Sullivan
  - Education and science. Memoranda, Carnegie Foundation report, National Research Council directory, speeches by Vannevar Bush, clipping, and printed articles, 1940-1955 (Folder 36: 2)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D. Memoranda, notes, press releases, clippings, printed articles, and typed excerpts from printed sources, 1945-1953 (Folder 36: 3)
  - Engineering. Press release, and conference materials re Centennial of Engineering, 1952 (Folder 36: 4)
  - Europe. Typed report by Karl von Wiegand, notes, clippings, and printed articles, 1947-1953 (Folder 36: 5)
  - Europe, Eastern. Clippings, memoranda, notes, and pamphlet (Breakdown: The Story of Michael Shipkov in the Hands of the Secret Police), 1946-1952 (Folder 36: 6)
  - European Recovery Program (Marshall Plan)
    - Correspondence, 1947-1948 (Folder 36: 7)
      Herbert Hoover correspondence with Bernard Baruch, Christian A. Herter, Julius Klein and others
    - Memoranda, 1947-1948 (Folder 36: 8)
    - Circulated documents
      - General, 1947-1948 (Folder 36: 9)
        Press releases, reports, and studies, by Charles S. Dewey, Julius Hirsch, E.E. Lincoln, the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, the United States Associates of the International Chambers of Commerce, the Women Investors Research Institute, and others
      - Committee for the Marshall Plan to Aid European Recovery issuances, 1947-1948 (Folder 37: 1)
        Leaflets, pamphlets, statements, studies, and printed appeals, by Dean Acheson, Robert P. Patterson, Henry L. Stimson, and others
      - Hazlitt, Henry, writings, 1947-1950 (Folder 37: 2)
        Statements, study issued in mimeographed form as "How Can America Rescue the World?" and in printed form as Will Dollars Save the World?, and pamphlet Illusions of Point Four
    - Printed matter, 1947-1951 (Folder 37: 3)
      Pamphlets, newsletters, and printed articles, including Grain Saving for United States Export issued by the Stanford University Food Research Institute, The Marshall Plan as American Policy issued by the Council on Foreign Relations, Marshall Plan Exposed by George W. Armstrong, A Statement on Foreign Aid issued by the Committee on the Present Danger, and radio broadcast transcripts by Henry J. Taylor
    - Clippings, 1947-1955 (Folder 37: 4)
    - Clippings (contd.), 1947-1955 (Folder 38: 1-3)
    - United States government documents
      - Congressional bills, 1947-1948 (Folder 39: 1)
      - Congressional reports
        - 1947 (Folder 39: 2-3)
        - 1948 (Folder 39: 4)
        - 1948 (contd.) (Folder 40: 1-4)
        - 1948 (contd.) (Folder 41: 1)
        - 1951 (Folder 41: 2)
      - Commodity reports, 1948 (Folder 41: 3)
      - Department of State issuances, 1947-1948 (Folder 41: 4)
        Study, report, and bulletins, including "Outline of a European Recovery Program," and Second Report to Congress on the United States Foreign Relief Program
      - Department of the Interior study, "National Resources and Foreign Aid,", 1947 (Folder 41: 5)
      - Economic Cooperation Administration report, A Report on Recovery Progress and United States Aid, 1949 (Folder 42: 1)
      - President's Committee on Foreign Aid report, European Recovery and American Aid, 1947 (Folder 42: 2-3)
        Includes preliminary mimeographed version and final published version
  - Food supply. Clippings, printed articles, pamphlets, study, and typed excerpts from printed sources, 1946-1954 (Folder 42: 4)
    Includes issuances of the Nutrition Foundation, the Stanford University Food Research Institute, and the Sugar Research Foundation
  - Foundation for Business Education. Correspondence between Herbert Hoover and John T. A. Ely, 1951-1952 (Folder 42: 5)
  - Germany
    - General. Memoranda, letter by Julius Klein, and clippings, 1946-1954 (Folder 42: 6)
    - Refugees. Typescript reports on plight of German refugees, 1945 (Folder 43: 1)
    - Soviet zone. Notes, typescript reports, clippings, and printed article, 1946-1948 (Folder 43: 2)
  - Great Britain. Notes, memoranda, speeches, clippings, and other printed matter, 1949-1954 (Folder 43: 3)
    Includes Kenneth de Courcy letter with British Treasury memorandum, and Anglo-American Council on Productivity reports
  - Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace. Memorandum and clipping, 1953-1957 (Folder 43: 4)
  - Ideology
    - Memoranda, 1943-1953 (Folder 43: 5)
    - Printed matter. Clippings, printed articles, pamphlets, and brochures, 1947-1955 (Folder 43: 6-7)
      Includes Americanism or Communism; The Fabulous Future; The Man in the Street Talks; Outlook for Freedom; The Palway Movement; The Way to Security
  - International Friendship League. Report, circa 1949 (Folder 44: 1)
  - International Trade Organization. Havana Charter for an International Trade Organization, 1948 (Folder 44: 2)
  - Japan. Memoranda, and typescript reports by James Lee Kauffman and by Harry Kern, 1947-1952 (Folder 44: 3)
  - Jewish Agricultural Society. Galleys of monograph by Gabriel Davidson, Our Jewish Farmers and the Story of the Jewish Agricultural Society, 1943 (Folder 44: 4)
  - Korea and Korean War. Memoranda, printed articles, clippings, and newsletters, 1950-1955 (Folder 44: 5)
    Includes typescript letter to the editor by Bonner Fellers
  - Labor-United States. Letters, memorandum, press release, clippings, pamphlets, and printed articles, 1935-1952 (Folder 44: 6-7)
    Includes The Law of Wages and of Prices and the Cost of Politics; A National Labor Policy; Wages and Labor Relations in the Railroad Industry, 1900-1941; Why the Taft-Hartley Law?
  - Latin America. Memoranda and printed article, 1948 (Folder 45: 1)
  - Law--United States. Memoranda and printed articles, 1949-1954 (Folder 45: 2)
  - London Naval Conference, 1930 (Folder 45: 3)
    Memoranda, clipping, photocopy of Herbert Hoover letter, and typed excerpts from printed sources, 1929-1944
  - MacArthur, Douglas
    - General. Transcripts of speeches by Douglas MacArthur, memoranda, clippings, and printed articles, 1950-1952 (Folder 45: 4)
    - United States Senate Armed Services Committee hearing transcripts on dismissal of Douglas MacArthur, 1951
      - Newspaper versions (Folder 45: 5-6)
      - U.S. News and World Report version (Folder 45: 7)
      - Typed excerpts (Folder 45: 8)
  - Marshall, George C. Clippings, printed articles, Congressional speeches, and typed excerpts from printed sources, 1947-1951 (Folder 45: 9)
  - Militarism and military policy. Memoranda, clippings, printed articles, Congressional speeches, and pamphlet ("We Are Not Helpless": How We Can Defend Ourselves against Atomic Weapons), 1950-1953 (Folder 46: 1)
  - Mutual Security Program. Memoranda, typed transcripts of letters, and Congressional report, 1950-1959 (Folder 46: 2)
  - North Atlantic Treaty Organization
    - Memoranda, notes, letter, press releases, and typed excerpts from printed sources, 1949-1953 (Folder 46: 3)
    - Printed matter. Clippings, bulletins, and pamphlet (The Atlantic Defense Pact), 1949-1953 (Folder 46: 4)
  - Nuremberg War Crime Trials. Transcript of introductory statement of proceedings, clippings, and typed excerpts from printed sources, 1945-1946 (Folder 46: 5-6)
  - Peace. Memoranda, printed texts of World War II peace treaties, and pamphlets, 1946-1950 (Folder 47: 1)
    Includes Bombs, Super-Bombs and the Cost of Peace; Swords into Plowshares
  - Peter I, Tsar of Russia. Memorandum by Frank Mason with typed transcript of purported will of Peter I, 1947 (Folder 47: 2)
  - Republican Party. Handbook of Organization, 1948 (Folder 47: 3)
  - Social Security System. Speeches, clippings, and pamphlet (Social Security and the Economics of Saving), 1948-1953 (Folder 47: 4)
  - Soviet Union
    - Memoranda and correspondence, 1939-1952 (Folder 47: 5)
    - Quotations from V. I. Lenin and Joseph Stalin, undated (Folder 47: 6)
      Typed transcripts
    - Khrushchev, Nikita, "Concerning the Cult of the Individual and Its Consequences." Mimeographed transcript of speech to 20th Congress of Communist Party of the Soviet Union, 1956 (Folder 47: 7)
    - Clippings, printed articles and bulletins, 1938-1956 (Folder 47: 8)
    - Pamphlets and serial issues, 1947-1952 (Folder 47: 9)
      Includes Petroliferous Provinces of Union of Soviet Socialist Republics; The Soviet Sugar Industry and Its Postwar Restoration; Stalinism: The One-Way Road to Bondage
  - Strategic metals. Memoranda, clippings, pamphlet (The Zinc Industry), and American Bureau of Metal Statistics yearbook, 1945-1953 (Folder 47: 10)
  - Tariffs and trade. Memoranda, notes, statistics, clippings, and serial issues, 1948-1955 (Folder 47: 11)
    Includes correspondence between Herbert Hoover and Harold Stassen
  - Truman, Harry S. Memorandum, clippings, printed articles, and Congressional speeches, 1950-1953 (Folder 48: 1)
  - Turkey. Memoranda, 1947 (Folder 48: 2)
  - United Foundation of U.S.A., Inc. Prospectus, 1951 (Folder 48: 3)
  - United Nations
    - Memoranda, letters, and circulated documents, 1950-1953 (Folder 48: 4)
    - Printed matter. Clippings, printed articles, Congressional speeches, bulletins, newsletters, pamphlets, and serial issues, 1945-1953 (Folder 48: 5-6)
      Includes Charter of the United Nations; Human Rights and the United Nations; Is an International Society Possible?
  - United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization. UNESCO Courier issues
    - 1949 (Folder 48: 7)
    - 1952-1953 (Folder 49: 1)
  - United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration
    - Circulated documents. Minutes, statements and reports
      - 1944 (Folder 49: 2-4)
      - 1945 (Folder 49: 5)
      - 1946 (Folder 50: 1-3)
      - 1946 (contd.) (Folder 51: 1)
    - Economic Notes (of UNRRA Italian Mission), 1947 (Folder 51: 2)
    - Monthly Review
      - 1944 (Folder 51: 3)
      - 1945 (Folder 51: 4-5)
      - 1946 (Folder 52: 1-2)
    - Memoranda and clippings, 1945-1946 (Folder 52: 3)
  - United States
    - Censorship. Letters, memoranda, speeches, and clippings, re secrecy of United States Department of State records, 1947-1950 (Folder 52: 4)
      Includes correspondence and speeches of Homer Ferguson
    - Economy
      - Correspondence, memoranda and notes, 1947-1953 (Folder 52: 5)
      - Economists' National Committee on Monetary Policy newsletters and pamphlets, 1951-1953 (Folder 52: 6)
        Includes Demonetizing the Federal Debt; Mr. Patman and the Federal Reserve System
      - National Industrial Conference Board bulletins, reports, and pamphlets, 1948-1953 (Folder 53: 1-2)
        Includes The Business Outlook 1949; Credit Policy; Key Materials; Postdefense Outlook; Price Control in a Defense Economy; Pros and Cons of Council of Economic Advisers' Policies
      - United States government reports and bulletins, 1949-1953 (Folder 53: 3-4)
      - Miscellaneous pamphlets and printed reports, 1945-1955 (Folder 54: 1-2)
      - Clippings and printed articles, 1949-1954 (Folder 54: 3)
    - Foreign policy
      - Correspondence and memoranda, 1946-1951 (Folder 54: 4)
        Includes letters by Bonner Fellers, Mark Sullivan, and Robert A. Taft
      - Clippings, printed articles, printed reports, and Congressional legislative calendars, 1946-1955 (Folder 54: 5)
      - Foreign Affairs issues, 1951-1953 (Folder 55: 1-2)
    - Politics
      - Correspondence, memoranda, and speeches, 1947-1952 (Folder 55: 3)
        Includes speeches by Alfred M. Landon and Robert A. Taft, and study by John Underhill and J. Harvie Williams, "Liberty and the Republic: The Case for Party Realignment"
      - Clippings and printed reports, 1947-1955 (Folder 55: 4)
        Includes pamphlet 15,000,000 Americans re race relations
      - Congressional Record proceedings, 1953 (Folder 56: 1)
    - United States. Commission on Organization of the Executive Branch of the Government (Hoover Commission)
      - Press releases and bulletins of the Commission and of the Citizens' Committee for Reorganization of the Executive Branch of the Government and the Citizens Committee for the Hoover Report, 1954-1957 (Folder 56: 2)
      - Federal agency lists, 1949 (Folder 56: 3)
      - Defense spending. Letter, memoranda, and clippings, 1951-1955 (Folder 56: 4)
      - Hydroelectric power and reclamation. Memoranda, clippings, and printed articles and reports, 1949-1956 (Folder 56: 5)
        Includes material on the Columbia Valley Administration, and report "Flood Protection in Kansas River Basin"
      - Lending programs. Memoranda, notes, bulletins, and clippings, 1951-1955 (Folder 56: 6)
      - National parks. Letter, memoranda, and printed article, 1952 (Folder 56: 7)
      - Lyons, Eugene. Typescript article by Lyons, "The Story Behind the Story of the Hoover Commission," with related correspondence and memoranda, 1947-1949 (Folder 56: 8)
      - Press coverage. Clippings and printed articles, 1949-1956 (Folder 57: 1)
        Includes Chamber of Commerce pamphlet Chaos in the Government, summarizing Commission findings
  - Universal Military Training Program. Letter, memoranda, Congressional bill, clippings, and printed articles, 1947-1952 (Folder 57: 2)
  - University of Buffalo. Clippings, 1939 (Folder 57: 3)
  - Wilson, Woodrow. Serialized biography by Ray Stannard Baker in New York Herald Tribune, 1929 (Folder 57: 4)
  - World Health Organization. Weekly Epidemiological Record issues, 1946-1947 (Folder 57: 5)
  - Yugoslavia. Internal United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration memorandum, and notes, 1946 (Folder 57: 6)
  - Zionism and Palestine
    - Correspondence of Herbert Hoover, 1943-1946 (Folder 57: 7)
    - Memoranda, 1943, undated (Folder 57: 8)
      Includes memorandum by the Jewish Agency for Palestine
    - Proclamation on the Moral Rights of the Stateless and Palestinian Jews. Printed text and related correspondence of Herbert Hoover, 1942-1943 (Folder 57: 9)
      Hoover was a signatory to the proclamation
    - Emergency Conference to Save the Jewish People of Europe, New York City, 1943 (Folder 57: 10)
      Program, resolutions, conference papers, press coverage, and correspondence of Herbert Hoover. Hoover was an honorary chairman of the conference. Includes papers presented to the conference by the Committee for a Jewish Army of Stateless and Palestinian Jews
    - Hebrew University of Jerusalem. Bulletins, development programs, and pamphlets, 1942-1945 (Folder 58: 1)
      Includes booklet The Hebrew University, Jerusalem: Its History and Development
    - Pamphlets and serial issues, 1943-1951 (Folder 58: 2-3)
      Includes The Arab Refugee Problem; British Labor and Zionism; Palestine: A Jewish Commonwealth in Our Time; Palestine: Land of Promise; Papers on Palestine; Technion Yearbook 1945
    - Clippings and printed articles, 1943-1946 (Folder 58: 4)
  - Miscellany. Letters, memoranda, notes, clippings, and publishers' catalogs, 1939-1953 (Folder 58: 5)
- Photographs, 1940, 1945 (Box 59)
  - Photographs of Herbert Hoover and others at Republican Party National Convention podium illustrating possible tampering with podium microphone, 1940 (Folder 59: 1)
    See also Herbert Hoover Speeches and Writings/"The Years as Crusader"
  - Photographs of emaciated German refugee children, 1945 (Folder 59: 2)
    See also General Subject File/Germany/Refugees
- Oversize File, 1926, 1947; 59 (Box 59)
  Oversize printed articles and statistical report
  - Printed articles from New Masses, 1926 (Folder 59: 3)
    See also Communist Subversion File/Communist Party issuances
  - United States Maritime Commission statistics relating to merchant marine losses during World War II, 1947 (Folder 59: 4)
    See also World War II Subject File